Guide to the Henry Geldzahler Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- December 1999 Acquisition, circa 1945-1996; 1; 39.04; (43 boxes)
  - Discerning Quality in Recent Art: talk at Parrish Art Museum, Southampton, N.Y. Lecture Notes: 1 page xerox typescript with hand corrections(2 copies); 10 page handwritten notes on 5 x 7" legal paper; 1 page handwritten notes on legal paper, 1984 August 23 (Box 19, Folder 13.6)
  - Jules Stein: article on the home of collection of Jules and Doris Stein, Hollywood collectors: 8 page xerox of article with Geldzahler's edits; 10 page original typescript with extensive edits by Geldzahler in red and black ink; 6 page typescript of further draft (5 pages xerox, 1 page original) with edits (Box 19, Folder 13.7)
  - Modern Art in America: 10 page original typescript with extensive edits in ink by Geldzahler; 10 page xerox of comparative illustrations ledger (Box 19, Folder 13.8)
  - Bibliography: 4 page listing of recent articles and texts by Geldzahler, circa 1980s (Box 19, Folder 13.9)
  - Selected Writings: A file containing xeroxes of texts by Geldzahler including: "Career and the Artist," "The Silver Era at Warhol's Factory," "Locating the Mirror in Modernism," "On George Condo," "Stueben Glass," "Keith Haring, 1990," Rainbow Room: The Art Program." (Box 19, Folder 13.1)
  - A Renewed Abstraction in Painting: 4 page original typescript with extensive edits in black ink, some cut and paste, 1990 (Box 19, Folder 13.11)
  - Managing the Arts: Wharton Business School magazine, extensive interview with Geldzahler (Box 19, Folder 13.12)
  - Pop Art in 1985: 1 page handwritten notes on legal paper (Box 19, Folder 13.13)
  - Domus mag: article with photos of Geldzahler's apartment at 33 West 9th Street, 1983 August (Box 19, Folder 13.14)
  - Underknowns: 8 page handwritten notes on legal paper, for PS1 exhibition (Box 19, Folder 13.15)
  - Colombia exhibition: letters, notes, slides, catalogues for exhibitions planned for Centro Colombo Americano exhibition space (Box 20, Folder 13.16)
  - Making it New: working materials for Geldzahler's book of collected essays and interviews: 3 page xeroxes of faxes regarding legal contract; circa 50 pages of faxes, correspondence notes (some original, mostly xeroxes) regarding all aspects of the book: Foreword by Hockney, Geldzahler's acknowledgments, corrections, selection of texts, book cover etc., Plus a large public relations file (Ira Silverberg, publicist) regarding book promotion. (Box 20, Folder 13.17)
  - Christopher Wilmarth: correspondence, photos, faxes regarding Geldzahler's Wilmarth exhibition at DIA Bridgehampton (Box 20, Folder 13.18)
  - Olympic Games, Atlanta: press info, requesting Geldzahler's involvement with visual arts program, 1996 (Box 20, Folder 13.19)
  - Bow Tie Business: info from a bow tie manufacturer seeking Geldzahler's participation in the business (Box 20, Folder 13.2)
  - Objects and Subjects in Warhol's Work: 37 page lecture transcript from the Art Gallery of Western Australia, hand corrected by Geldzahler in blue ink, through page 12; a second copy, uncorrected. Cover letter from lecture hosts. (Box 20, Folder 13.21)
  - Christopher Wilmarth Estate: letters and notes (mostly original) regarding the estate of CW; numerous letters from his widow, Susan Wilmarth (Box 20, Folder 13.22)
  - Modern Art in America: chapters 1-6, xeroxes, some cut and pasted (Box 20, Folder 13.23)
  - Nelson Lecture Agency: correspondence with lecture agency, 7 pages, 1992 January (Box 20, Folder 13.24)
  - Decorative Arts: "Kissing Cousins: Kinships and Distinctions/Native America and Fifties Italy." Original 3 page typescript with extensive edits in blue and black ink, text for Martin Cohen Gallery. Five snapshots of Italian glass vases, circa 1992 (Box 20, Folder 13.25)
  - Joseph Geldzahler (Father) Funeral Speech: 16 page handwritten notes on legal paper; 4 page original typescript with corrections in blue ink; numerous letters of condolence (Box 20, Folder 13.26)
  - Photos of Geldzahler: a file of photos of Geldzahler, ill, taken by Laurie Lambrecht, 1994 July 17 (Box 20, Folder 13.27)
  - Modern Art in America: two chapters: Frank Lloyd Wright and Louis Comfort Tiffany; Duchamp and Picabia: circa 60 pages of original typescript, heavily edited with cutting and pasting; circa 26 pages xeroxed typescript with orig edits in black ink; circa 35 pages handwritten notes on legal paper (Box 20, Folder 13.28)
  - Modern Art in America: Frank Lloyd Wright and Louis Comfort Tiffany: 12 page handwritten notes on 5 x 7" legal pad; 2 pages handwritten notes on legal paper; 14 page typescript heavily edited with cutting and pasting; circa 40 page xeroxed typescript with corrections (Box 20, Folder 13.29)
  - Modern Art in America: preface, revised with notes by RF; xeroxed typescript of Chapters 4 (Stieglitz) and 5 (Armory Show) (Box 20, Folder 13.3)
  - Modern Art in America: chapter 7: Regionalism (Box 20, Folder 13.31)
  - Hockney fax exhibition: circa 100 pages of faxes by Hockney, with some correspondence and writings by Geldzahler on an exhibition made by Hockney in California and faxed to a gallery in Brazil (Box 20, Folder 13.32)
  - Last Note: copy of last note (written to Randall Bourscheidt) (Box 20, Folder 13.33)
  - Obituary file: numerous obituary notices of Geldzahler from NY Times, Southampton Press, NY Observer, Time magazine etc. (Box 20, Folder 13.34)
  - Memorial Service at MET: invitation and programs to Geldzahler memorial service at the MET Museum (Box 20, Folder 13.35)
  - Audiocassettes
    - "What I know about Photography", lecture by Henry Geldzahler at Museo de Monterrey in Mexico. Total time 48:00 min., 1992 May 14 (Box 21, Folder A1)
    - "Objects and Subjects in Warhol's Art", lecture by Henry Geldzahler at the Art of Western Australia, Perth, Australia, 6 - 7.15 PM, 1994 March 1 (Box 21, Folder A2)
    - "Objects and Subjects in Warhol's Art", lecture by Henry Geldzahler at the Museum of Contemporary Art, Sydney, Australia, poor quality sound because it was taped from VCR tape, 1994 February 23 (Box 21, Folder A3)
    - Dale Chihuly on his own work, tape # 1, 1985 December 17 (Box 21, Folder A4)
    - "The Sixties the Way They Were", lecture by Henry Geldzahler at Guild Hall in East Hampton, 1991 September 22 (Box 21, Folder A5)
    - Master tape of a First Interview between Henry Geldzahler and Jules Olitski, 1990 April 11 (Box 21, Folder A6)
    - Master tape of an Second Interview between Henry Geldzahler and Jules Olitski, 1994 April 20 (Box 21, Folder A7)
    - Project Talking Pictures, this is a short recording by Henry Geldzahler on a photograph by Consuela Canaga that he had chosen as a picture to talk about. This is a last recording that Henry did (Box 21, Folder A8)
    - Lecture at FAWC - Fine Arts Works Center in Provincetown, MA. Lecture is about sixties and the way they were. Approximate time 60:00 min., 1991 December 14 (Box 21, Folder A9)
    - Side 1; Story on Ellsworth Kelly at FWAM, by a reporter Joan Davidow, aired 10.14.1987 on radio station KERA 90.1, Dallas/Ft. Worth/ Denton. Side 2; Interview of Henry Geldzahler by Joan Davidow for the story above., 1987 October 14 (Box 21, Folder A10)
    - Tel Aviv Symposium (Box 21, Folder A11)
    - Henry Geldzahler Speaking to Southampton Artists, 1989 June 23 (Box 21, Folder A12)
    - Tape of phone conversation between Henry Geldzahler and Dale Chihuly (Box 21, Folder A13)
    - Unidentified tape (Box 21)
    - Henry Geldzahler - "Making It New", [198?] March 29 (Box 21)
    - David Hockney - "Reading of 'Blue Guitar' by Wallace Stevens, 1994 August (Box 21)
  - Video Recordings
    - UCLA Lecture by Henry Geldzahler, 1984 February; YCALMSS684_0069; 1; 01:01:49 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418077)
    - Geldzahler/Hockney Conversation at the National Gallery of Art, 1985 January 20; YCALMSS684_0038; 1; 01:24:24 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418085)
    - Dale Chihuly, ½ hour, [no year] April 21; YCALMSS684_0039; 1; 00:35:41 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418093)
      The tape ends with a partial recording of "LA Law".
    - Chihuly Compilation III, total time: 65:30, circa 1993; YCALMSS684_0040; 1; 01:02:33 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418101)
      1) KCTS 9 Chihuly Special, 07.29.1992., time 30:00 min.; 2) CBS Sunday Morning, 03.31.1993., time 10:00 min.; 3) Team Chihuly at S.A.M., 06.10.1993., time 14:00 min.; 4) KCTS 9 Special - Pelleas and Melisande, time 13:00 min.
    - Henry Geldzahler "Alice Neel at DIA Center for the Arts in Bridgehampton", 1991 July 25; YCALMSS684_0041; 1; 00:23:23 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418119)
    - Peter Sempel: "Jonas in the Desert" - work in progress, time 20 min., and Extra 3 min. Henry Geldzahler at the Anthology Film Archives., 1993 July; YCALMSS684_0042; 1; 00:24:05 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418127)
    - A Gathering of Family and Friends in Memory of Henry Geldzahler, 1935-1994, The Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1994 October 3; YCALMSS684_0043; 1; 01:04:28 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418135)
    - Interview between Henry Geldzahler and Francesco Clemente at Philadelphia Museum of Art, 1990 October 28; YCALMSS684_0044; 1; 00:53:26 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418143)
    - Geldzahler Family, 1990 April 5; YCALMSS684_0045; 1; 00:04:25 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418150)
    - Dale Chihuly - CBS Sunday Morning. Total time 10:00 min., 1992-09-27; YCALMSS684_0046; 1; 00:10:32; This copy of YCALMSS684_0047 is incomplete. (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418168)
    - Dale Chihuly - CBS Sunday Morning. Total time 10:00 min. (duplicate?), 1993 March 31; YCALMSS684_0047; 1; 00:09:33 (Box 22, Item barcode 39002102418176)
    - Team Chihuly at S.A.M. / Slide and Video Presentation. Total time 14:00 min., 1993 June 10; YCALMSS684_0048; 1; 00:13:18 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098938971)
    - "Pelleas and Melisande" Chihuly Special, KCTS 9, Produced by Gary Gibson, Aired 03.14.93 and 04.13.1993. Total time 13:00 min., YCALMSS684_0049; 1; 00:13:26 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098938989)
    - "The Late Show / de Kooning", produced by BBC, NTSC system, YCALMSS684_0050; 1; 00:48:46 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098938997)
    - "Late Show / The de Kooning Affair - ex. Spool HR83425", produced by BBC TV, NTSC system, 1991-01-13; YCALMSS684_0051; 1; 00:48:14 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098939003)
    - "Petroglyph Vessels by William Morris", produced by Jeffrey Pedersen of Signal Hill, Inc. Art and Industrial Film, 2421 E. 16th Street, Los Angeles, CA 90021, Total time 7:00 min, undated; YCALMSS684_0052; 1; 00:07:59 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098939011)
    - Interview with Henry Geldzahler, camera master # 1, CBC, [Betacam with VHS dub], 1987 May 14; YCALMSS684_0053; 1; 00:18:54 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098939029)
    - Interview with Henry Geldzahler, camera master # 2, CBC [Betacam with VHS Dub], 1987 May 14; YCALMSS684_0054; 00:11:37 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098939037)
    - Interview with Henry Geldzahler, camera master # 1 (DUB), CBC, 1999-11-01; YCALMSS684_0055; 1; 00:18:32 (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098939045)
      The original date of the interview was 1987-03-14.
    - Interview with Henry Geldzahler, camera master # 2 (DUB), CBC, 1999-11-01; YCALMSS684_0056; 1; 00:11:26; A timecode runs through the video. The date of the original production reads 1987-03-14. (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098939052)
    - Interview with Henry Geldzahler, camera master # 1 and #2, CBC, (DUB), undated; YCALMSS684_0057; 1; 00:50:43; [Magnetoscope] HI-FI sealment (Box 23, Item barcode 39002098939060)
    - "Chihuly", KCTS 9 Television Special, "Installations 1964 - 1992. At Seattle Art Museum". Total time 30:00 min. (Copy 1 of 2), 1992 July 29; YCALMSS684_0001; 1; 00:29:46; This is a duplicate copy. It was of the best quality and digitized. (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349074)
    - "Chihuly", KCTS 9 Television Special, "Installations 1964 - 1992. At Seattle Art Museum". Total time 30:00 min. (Copy 2 of 2), 1992 July 29; 1; This tape was not digitized. See copy YCALMSS684_0001 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349082)
    - "Interview of Henry Geldzahler by James (Mellon) Curley", Produced by Carnegie Institute of Pittsburgh, PA for Andy Warhol Museum at DIA Center for the Arts in NYC on 22nd Street, Robert J. Passaro, 251 Twin Hills Drive, Pittsburgh, PA 15216 -1107 was cameraman, Total time 14:30 min., 1992 December 10; YCALMSS684_0002; 1; 00:16:02 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349090)
    - Tape with two movies by Andy Warhol: David Hockney at the Factory, very short or not taped in full, 1981; The Empress and The Commissioner, 1980. Conversation between Diana Vreeland and Henry Geldzahler at Mrs's Vreeland Apartment, 1980-1981; YCALMSS684_0003; 1; 00:30:29 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349108)
    - David Hockney video of Montcalm Studio Portraits of Friends and Dogs, Gouache drawings. Copyright David Hockney 1994., 1994 April 12-13; YCALMSS684_0004; 1; 01:20:34 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349116)
    - David Hockney video of OPERALIA '94 STAGE DESIGNS, 1994 July 19; YCALMSS684_0005; 1; 01:25:04 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349124)
    - David Hockney video of OPERALIA' 94 STAGE DESIGNS, tape edit 3; 1" model, copyright David Hockney/ Ian Falconer, Total time 81:00 min., 1994 August 3; YCALMSS684_0006; 1; 01:24:17 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349132)
    - Henry Geldzahler's lecture "Object and Subject in Warhol Art", at the Art Gallery of Western Australia, Perth, Australia, 6 - 7.15 PM, 1994 March 1; YCALMSS684_0007; 1; 01:17:27 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349140)
    - Interview of Henry Geldzahler on Andrew Wyeth (and in general on Wyeths) relating to a show that was held at National Gallery of Art in Washington, D.C. in 1987, It was done by CBC or CBS ?, Total time 28:00 min. (tape 1 of 2), YCALMSS684_0008; 1; 00:28:24 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349157)
    - Interview of Henry Geldzahler on Andrew Wyeth (and in general on Wyeths) relating to a show that was held at National Gallery of Art in Washington, D.C. in 1987, It was done by CBC or CBS ?, Total time 28:00 min. (tape 2 of 2), YCALMSS684_0009; 1; 00:28:55 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349165)
    - Tape from BBC TV film department from program "The Late Show Pop Art", 1991 June 12; 1; 01:56:54 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349173)
    - "Travels with Henry Geldzahler and David Hockney in Alaska". Total time 13:55 min., 1990 July; YCALMSS684_0011; 1; 02:13:27; The sound is very low on this tape. (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349181)
    - Movie "Superstar; The Life and Times of Andy Warhol", American Masters, YCALMSS684_0012; 1; 01:29:36 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349199)
    - [File number not used] (Box 24, Folder V28)
    - Interview of Jules Olitski by Henry Geldzahler, part one, 1990 April 11; YCALMSS684_0013; 1; 01:59:15 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349207)
    - Interview of Jules Olitski by Henry Geldzahler, part one, 1990 April 12; YCALMSS684_0014; 1; 01:54:18 (Box 24, Item barcode 39002102349215)
    - Tape of Henry Geldzahler talking about Andy Warhol at DIA Center for the Arts in Bridgehampton, "Memorial show for Andy Warhol", Nicholas Maravell, 1987 July 3; YCALMSS684_0058; 1; 00:18:41 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939078)
    - "The Sixties the Way they Were" - lecture by Henry Geldzahler at FAWC (Fine Arts Works Center) Provincetown, Massachusetts., 1991 December 14; YCALMSS684_0059; 1; 01:04:31 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939086)
    - Tape of Dinner in Honor of Roy Lichtenstein at National Arts Club, one of the speakers is Henry Geldzahler, 1994 January 13; YCALMSS684_0060; 1; 01:01:34 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939094)
      A note to Henry Geldzahler from National Arts Club President Aldon James Jr., dated 1994-02-28, reads: Dear Henry, It was so exciting to have you speak at our Lichtenstein Dinner. You have a tradition of club involvement going back many years which we value. Return, soon. Sincerely, Aldon James.
    - "What I know about Photography," lecture by Henry Geldzahler at Museo de Monterrey in Monterrey, Mexico, 1992 May 14; YCALMSS684_0061; 1; 00:57:03 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939102)
    - Henry Geldzahler, Ingber Gallery Presents, undated; YCALMSS684_0062; 1; 00:44:32 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939110)
      A date appears at the beginning of the video, 1988-08-07.
    - Visit to Edmonton, Canada. Some interviews and partial lecture at Myer Horowitz Theater, presented by Open Gallery, 1993 September 10; YCALMSS684_0063; 1; 00:32:50 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939128)
    - Henry Geldzahler and Dale Chihuly, Art Glass, 1988 July 28; YCALMSS684_0064; 1; 00:54:46 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939136)
    - Henry Geldzahler Lecture at Ascher Edelman Foundation, Laussane, Switzerland, 1991 August; YCALMSS684_0065; 1; 00:51:54 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939144)
    - David Hockney's Show at Andre Emmerich Gallery in NYC, 1993 January 30; YCALMSS684_0066; 1; 00:06:17 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939151)
    - Henry Geldzahler lecture on Alice Neel, 1986 April 8; YCALMSS684_0067; 1; 01:20:42 (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939169)
    - Henry Geldzahler lecture "Subject Object", Museum of Contemporary Art. Time 80:00 min, undated; YCALMSS684_0068; 1; 01:26:23; NTSC (Box 25, Item barcode 39002098939177)
    - [File number not used] (Box 25, Folder V35)
  - Photograph File
    - Geldzahler in Melbourne with Randy Hunt and Australian art critic Maureen Gilchrist, circa 1977 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Geldzahler presenting an award to de Kooning at Guggenheim Museum, 1979 April 26 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Geldzahler with Christo and Jean-Claude Christo, in Geldzahler's NYC Commissioner's office (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Geldzahler at awards dinner with Bernice Abbott, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Geldzahler speaking at an Art News conference, 1982 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Geldzahler, D Hockney, Sir John Pope-Hennessey, at DH opening, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Geldzahler presenting an award to Ellsworth Kelly, (one 8 x 10, one 5 x 7), circa 1980 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Portrait of Geldzahler at 33 West 9th Street (bedroom) with Panama hat and bowtie, circa 1979 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Geldzahler and Robert Motherwell, NY, by Renate Motherwell, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Geldzahler with Robert and Renate Motherwell, circa 1980 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - DH painting Steve Mazoh's pool, Rhinebeck, NY; 7 color snapshots, 9 color 8 x 10s, circa 1978 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Geldzahler, DH, Paul Cornwall-Jones, Nathan Kolodner, Kasmin, at DH opening at Emmerich Gallery, 1981 March 26 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Geldzahler, Chris Wilmarth, Nancy Graves, Stratford Ontario, opening of Geldzahler's American Accents exhibition. 3 copies, color, circa 1983 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Photo of drawing by Don Bachardy of Geldzahler, 1969 October 28 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Geldzahler and Helen Frankenthaler, in silhouette, looking at large painted canvas by HF, possibly stage dropage, undated (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Geldzahler in cowboy shirt, with Tanya Grosman at NYU opening, 1977 February 22 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Geldzahler, Ellsworth Kelly, Frank Stella (and Annalee Newman?), circa 1980 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Geldzahler with goatee, probably at Harvard, circa 1958 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Geldzahler and AW at the factory, by DH. Print from a copy negative, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Geldzahler portrait by R C White, circa 1990 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - Geldzahler with Ellsworth Kelly installing his room at NYPS exhibit, 1970 October (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - Geldzahler with Larry River and R Rauschenberg, circa 1975 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - Photo of painting by Hockney: Geldzahler and Christopher Scott (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - Studio portrait of Geldzahler by John Schupf, circa 1989 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Two photos of Geldzahler in Hat, coat, with cigar, circa 1979 (Box 26, Folder 25)
    - Geldzahler sculpture by George Segal, 1963 (Box 26, Folder 26)
    - Contact strip #76459 by Duane Michaels; Geldzahler in his apartment, in background Ron Davis painting, in foreground Motherwell Gauloise cigarette pack collage (print), circa 1970s (Box 26, Folder 27)
    - Geldzahler in a Claes Oldenburg happening, circa 1965 (Box 26, Folder 28)
    - Geldzahler on bed in front of leaded glass windows, some close-up, one photo hanging Warhol Marilyns (8 photos), circa 1965 (Box 26, Folder 29)
    - Geldzahler portrait, circa 1960 (Box 26, Folder 30)
    - Geldzahler portrait with goatee, circa 1958 (Box 26, Folder 31)
    - Geldzahler portrait with cigar, circa 1965 (Box 26, Folder 32)
    - 12 photos of DH and Geldzahler in Brussels, 1992 (Box 26, Folder 33)
    - Bob Miller, DH, Geldzahler, Bob Miller's house in Hamptons, 3 prints, circa 1978 (Box 26, Folder 34)
    - Geldzahler on boat in cowboy hat, circa 1976 (Box 26, Folder 35)
    - Geldzahler portrait, mirrored glasses, circa 1974 (Box 26, Folder 36)
    - Geldzahler and DH (color), circa 1979 (Box 26, Folder 37)
    - Geldzahler in panama hat with drink in hand, photo by Sally Edelman, circa 1977 (Box 26, Folder 38)
    - Geldzahler with papier maché lizard (at Met?), circa 1966 (Box 26, Folder 39)
    - 3 photos of Geldzahler sitting under a tree. His "official" DCA photo, circa 1979 (Box 26, Folder 40)
    - Ten 5 x 7" photos by Patrick McMullen of the Palladium nightclub opening, circa 1980 (Box 26, Folder 41)
    - Two photo reproductions of Don Bachardy drawing of Christopher Scott, 1970 January 25 (Box 26, Folder 42)
    - Geldzahler and unidentified woman, circa 1980 (Box 26, Folder 43)
    - Chris Scott, Geldzahler (in cape), Robert Irwin, at an opening, circa 1967 (Box 26, Folder 44)
    - Geldzahler and unidentified man (Charles Byron?) next to a Magritte painting, circa 1980 (Box 26, Folder 45)
    - 2 photos of Geldzahler curated opening at Columbus Circle, Department of Cultural Affairs office, Geldzahler, Michael Hurson, Raymond Foye; Hockney, Louise Bourgeoise, Lily Auchincloss (Box 26, Folder 46)
    - Eight vintage prints of Geldzahler by John Warman for the Herald Tribune, circa 1965 (Box 26, Folder 47)
    - 2 photos: Geldzahler, D Hockney and Nick Rea; Nick Rea with cigar, circa 1973 (Box 26, Folder 48)
    - Unidentified male nude, prob photographed by Arthur Lambert (Box 26, Folder 49)
    - Frank Stella, circa 1960 (Box 26, Folder 50)
    - Geldzahler and Ian Falconner, three color 5 x 7 photos, 1979 August (Box 26, Folder 51)
    - Twenty-seven photos (a few snapshots and 5 x 7s) of Geldzahler in his official role as Commissioner of Cultural Affairs, NYC. Including his swearing-in ceremony at City Hall with Mayor Koch (Box 26, Folder 52)
    - Family snapshots, some in color (Box 26, Folder 53)
    - Portraits of Geldzahler (Box 26)
    - Geldzahler at functions and galleries (Box 26)
    - Geldzahler and David Hockney (Box 26)
    - Pictures taken by Andy Warhol (Box 26)
    - Photographs, 2 (Box 26)
    - Slides and color transparencies, 9 (Box 27)
  - Uncataloged files, 23 (Box 28)
  - Uncataloged files, 26 (Box 29)
  - Uncataloged files, 42 (Box 30)
  - Printed material, 16 (Box 31)
  - Memorabilia, 7 (Box 32)
  - Objects, 5 (Box 33)
  - Charles Ludlum: 8x10 B&W photographs and contact sheets of Charles Ludlum, avant garde theatre producer, playwright and actor - and director. (Box 34 (Oversize))
  - Magazines, 3 (Box 34 (Oversize))
  - Magazines and printed material, 2 (Box 35 (Oversize))
  - Department of Cultural Affairs scrapbook: photos, press release and press clippings related to NYPS exhibition. (Box 36 (Oversize))
  - Photographs, 5 (Box 37 (Oversize))
  - Photograph album (Box 38 (Oversize))
  - Vacation photograph album (Box 39 (Oversize))
  - Vacation photograph album (Box 40 (Oversize))
  - Printed material and artwork, 6 (Box 41 (Oversize))
  - Memorabilia (Box 42)
  - Wire bound book (Box 43)